{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Alaska","incorrectAnswers":["Hawaii","Arizona","New Mexico"],"question":"Which US state was the second-to-last to join the Union?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Algeria","incorrectAnswers":["Cameroon","Democratic Republic of the Congo","Senegal"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Algiers?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Niger–Congo","incorrectAnswers":["Dravidian","Uralic","Japonic"],"question":"The language 'Zulu' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"An aria","incorrectAnswers":["A duet","An adiago","A dirge"],"question":"What is the term for a solo song in an opera?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bow Wow Wow","incorrectAnswers":["Starland Vocal Band","Jane Child","M"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1982 with I Want Candy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["Ecuador","Iraq","Scotland"],"question":"In which country would you find the Great Barrier Reef?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"A Siege Machine","incorrectAnswers":["A Scientific Instrument","A Position in the Church","A Tax on Feudal Landowners"],"question":"What Was A Ballista?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belgium","incorrectAnswers":["Austria","France","Switzerland"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of La Grand-Place?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"A Day in the Life\" by the Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["\"Let it Be\" by the Beatles","\"Yo Home to Bel-Air\"","\"Old Man\" by Neil Young"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"I read the news today, oh boy...\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"A shield","incorrectAnswers":["A sword","A helmet","A spear"],"question":"Used by the Roman military, what was a Scutum?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","The United Kingdom","Spain"],"question":"In 1956, Tunisia gained independence from which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Seychelles","incorrectAnswers":["Madagascar","Costa Rica","Comoros"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.sc' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"ABBA","incorrectAnswers":["In Flames","HammerFall","Katatonia"],"question":"Which Swedish pop group released the song 'Happy New Year'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Musical Youth","incorrectAnswers":["House of Pain","Aqua","Digable Planets"],"question":"'Pass the Dutchie' was a one hit wonder in 1983 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Radiohead","incorrectAnswers":["Goldfrapp","Cream","Girls Aloud"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Creep'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Niger–Congo","Afroasiatic","Dravidian"],"question":"The language 'German' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Franz Kafka","incorrectAnswers":["Émile Zola","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Leo Tolstoy"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Metamorphosis'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Edgar Rice Burroughs","incorrectAnswers":["Jack Vance","George R. R. Martin","Robert A. Heinlein"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Pellucidar heptalogy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Post-Impressionism","incorrectAnswers":["Abstract expressionism","Cubism","Ukiyo-e"],"question":"The painting \"Starry Night\" by Vincent van Gogh is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Oracle","incorrectAnswers":["Microsoft","Yahoo","Google"],"question":"In the year 2000 which companies CEO was the worlds second richest man?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Pennsylvania","incorrectAnswers":["Ohio","Maryland","Delaware"],"question":"In which American state is George A. Romero's 1968 film 'Night Of The Living Dead' set?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Egypt","incorrectAnswers":["Greece","Australia","Italy"],"question":"In which country was the Rosetta Stone found?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Flower Buds ","incorrectAnswers":["Fish Eggs","Berries","Fermented Tubers"],"question":"Capers Are Derived From What?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Vichy","incorrectAnswers":["De Gaulle","Soire","Truffaut"],"question":"What Was The Name Given To The French Goverment Which Collaborated With The Nazis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Modernism","incorrectAnswers":["Pointillism","Primitivism","Ukiyo-e"],"question":"The painting \"American Gothic\" by ‎Grant Wood is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Bay of Pigs","incorrectAnswers":["Bay of Cows","Bay of Dogs","Bay of Sharks"],"question":"What is the name given to the USA's failed 1961 invasion of Cuba?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Portuguese ","incorrectAnswers":["Spanish","English","French"],"question":"What Is The Main Language Spoken In Brazil?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"American Football","incorrectAnswers":["Horse Racing","Tennis","Cycling"],"question":"Which sport is played at The Super Bowl?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"St. louis","incorrectAnswers":["New York City","Washington, D.C.","Los Angeles"],"question":"___________ was called the \"Gateway to the West\" in the 1800s because it served as a starting place for wagon train departures.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Democratic Republic of the Congo","incorrectAnswers":["Nigeria","Ethiopia","Egypt"],"question":"What is the name of the second-largest country in Africa by area?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Motor Racing","Ice Hockey","Figure skating"],"question":"With which sport is Tegla Laroupe associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dominican Republic","incorrectAnswers":["Antigua and Barbuda","Venezuela","Tanzania"],"question":"Santo Domingo is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roland Emmerich","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Independence Day?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kansas","incorrectAnswers":["Iowa","Ohio","Nebraska"],"question":"In which US state is the fictional hometown of Superman?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"As You Like It","incorrectAnswers":["The Twelfth Night","A Midsummer Night's Dream","Richard III"],"question":"Which Shakespearean play is set in the forest of Arden?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alice Munro","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","E. T. A. Hoffmann","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Lying Under the Apple Tree'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Goonies","incorrectAnswers":["E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial","Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom","Back to the Future"],"question":"Which 1985 Steven Spielberg film features the actor who played Samwise Gamgee in The Lord of the Rings?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"poisons","incorrectAnswers":["life","vibrations and oscillations in the Sun","the historical study of languages"],"question":"What is Toxicology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Voltaire","incorrectAnswers":["Rousseau","Hugo","Flaubert"],"question":"Which author of \"Candide\" said, \"The secret of being a bore is to tell everything\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Shawshank Redemption","incorrectAnswers":["Double Indemnity","North by Northwest","Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'Two imprisoned men bond over a number of years, finding redemption through acts of common decency.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tanzania","incorrectAnswers":["Senegal","Algeria","South Africa"],"question":"Dar es Salaam is a city in which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Night of the Hunter","incorrectAnswers":["Jaws","Fatal Attraction","The Wizard of Oz"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Rev. Harry Powell'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Well, nobody's perfect.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Nobody puts Baby in a corner.\"","\"My mother thanks you. My father thanks you. My sister thanks you. And I thank you.\"","\"I'll have what she's having.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Some Like It Hot'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mandarin","incorrectAnswers":["Hausa","Chewa","Urdu"],"question":"Which of these languages would you find spoken in Taiwan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Claret ","incorrectAnswers":["Burgundy","Merlot","Shiraz"],"question":"What name is given to the red wines from the Bordeaux region?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Daniel Craig","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Connery","Roger Moore","Timothy Dalton"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Skyfall?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Britney Spears","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Alanis Morissette","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, dancer and actress released the studio album 'Circus'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1996","incorrectAnswers":["1992","2000","2004"],"question":"In which year was Trainspotting released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kathy Bates","incorrectAnswers":["Judy Garland","Glenn Close","Olivia Newton-John"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Annie Wilkes in Misery?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Pirates of the Caribbean","incorrectAnswers":["The Godfather","The Silence of the Lambs","The Birds"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Captain Jack Sparrow'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Una hirundo non facit ver","incorrectAnswers":["Carpe diem","Dies irae","Faber est suae quisque fortunae"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases means 'One swallow does not make summer'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Damascus","incorrectAnswers":["Rome","Beijing","Cairo"],"question":"What Is The Oldest Continuously Inhabited City In The World","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Valet","incorrectAnswers":["Chef","Doctor","Assassin"],"question":"In P.G. Wodehouse's novels, what is the job that Jeeves has? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Anthony Hopkins","incorrectAnswers":["Riz Ahmed","Chadwick Boseman","Gary Oldman"],"question":"Who won the 2020 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Anthony in The Father?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mazda","incorrectAnswers":["Mercedez-Benz","Ford","Greyhound"],"question":"'Zoom Zoom' is a slogan associated with which motoring brand?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Velociraptor","incorrectAnswers":["T-Rex","Stegosaurus","Triceratops"],"question":"Which dinosaur, made famous by 'Jurassic Park', had a 'killing claw' on each foot and was around six feet long?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Ryder Cup","incorrectAnswers":["The FIFA World Cup","The UEFA Champion's League","The America's Cup"],"question":"The Solheim Cup Is The Woman's Equivalent Of Which Famous Sporting Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The United Kingdom","incorrectAnswers":["Cuba","Indonesia","India"],"question":"Where in the world was Chicken Tikka Masala invented?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Alma Mater","incorrectAnswers":["Maxima Cum Laude","Curriculum Vitae","Magna Cum Laude"],"question":"What Latin term is used to refer to the university that someone attended?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Can't Buy Me Love'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Pete Sampras","incorrectAnswers":["Pete Roddick","Pete Hewitt","Pete Federer"],"question":"Who is known as Pistol Pete?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Billy the Kid","incorrectAnswers":["Butch Cassidy","Jesse James","Buffalo Bill"],"question":"Which Wild West legend was born Henry McCarty?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ginger Spice","incorrectAnswers":["Scary Spice","Baby Spice","Posh Spice"],"question":"Which Spice Girl made a guest appearance in an episode of Sex and the City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Captain Kirk","incorrectAnswers":["Luke Skywalker","Charles Foster Kane","E.T."],"question":"In the Halloween films, Michael Myers wears a painted mask of which character?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Liberator of Latin American countries","incorrectAnswers":["Greek philosopher.","Dentist who pioneered the use of anaesthetic.","German Communist philosopher."],"question":"Which of the following describes Simon Bolivar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Blatherskite","incorrectAnswers":["Agastopia","Cacophony","Impignorate"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a person who talks at great length without making much sense'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A Pickle","incorrectAnswers":["A Potato","An Onion","A Cherry"],"question":"A German tradition is to hide a certain food in a Christmas tree, and the first one to find it gets a special gift. What is the food they hide?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mila Kunis","incorrectAnswers":["Jacqueline Bisset","Sophia Loren","Madonna"],"question":"Which actress has acted in both That '70s Show and Black Swan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Santiago","incorrectAnswers":["Castries","Manama","Port Vila"],"question":"What is the capital city of Chile?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Vasco da Gama","incorrectAnswers":["James Watt","Constantine the Great","William Shakespeare"],"question":"Which influential explorer was the first European to reach India and establish a route for imperialism?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Minnesota","incorrectAnswers":["Iowa","Michigan","Wisconsin"],"question":"Which of the 48 contiguous states extends farthest north?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dublin ","incorrectAnswers":["Lisbon","Budapest","Oslo"],"question":"Which European City's Name Means 'Black Pool'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Conan","incorrectAnswers":["Hercules","Thor","Xena"],"question":"Which character was accompanied by a wizard named Akiro in two 1980s movies?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Here's looking at you, kid.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Attica! Attica!\"","\"What a dump.\"","\"I have always depended on the kindness of strangers.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Casablanca'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"species","incorrectAnswers":["family","order","class"],"question":"What is the major subdivision of a genus or subgenus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The spin","incorrectAnswers":["The tumble","The shake","The toss"],"question":"What is the name of the cycle in a washing machine that dries clothes?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the studio album 'How to Dismantle an Atomic Bomb'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rage Against the Machine","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American band released the studio album 'Evil Empire'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ulysses","incorrectAnswers":["My Life As a Man","On the Road","Post Office"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Molly Bloom'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Trinity","incorrectAnswers":["Little Boy","Fat Man","Big Bang"],"question":"What was the name of the first nuclear bomb tested by the United States?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cycling","incorrectAnswers":["Motor racing","Gymnastics","Hockey"],"question":"With which sport is Jacques Anquetil associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Great Wall of China","incorrectAnswers":["The Panama Canal","The Golden Gate Bridge","The Hoover Dam"],"question":"Which of these structures stretches for over 4,000 miles, often called the largest building project ever completed?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Valley of Fear'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","Brazil","Canada"],"question":"Which country has the longest land border?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Philip Reeve","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Robert Louis Stevenson","Christopher Tolkien"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Mortal Engines Quartet'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1990","incorrectAnswers":["1984","1994","1999"],"question":"When did the demolition of the Berlin wall begin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Flushing Meadows","incorrectAnswers":["Newport Casino","Orange Tennis Club","Philadelphia Cricket Club"],"question":"The US Tennis Open takes place at which venue?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["United States","Pakistan","Australia"],"question":"Where is the film industry of Bollywood located?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","Albania","Switzerland"],"question":"In which country is the city of Berlin?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1975","incorrectAnswers":["1969","1980","1984"],"question":"The war in Vietnam ended with the fall of Saigon in what year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Guns N' Roses","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American hard rock band released the album 'Appetite for Destruction'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Crete","incorrectAnswers":["Minoa","Lesbos","Rhodes"],"question":"In Greek mythology, what was Minos the king of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Paintings","incorrectAnswers":["Crowns","Fingers","Books"],"question":"What did Jan Vermeer give two of to a baker in exchange for credit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Empire State Building","incorrectAnswers":["The Chrysler Building","The World Trade Center","The CN Tower"],"question":"On May 1st 1931 the world's then tallest building was opened in New York City. Which building was it?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["JRR Tolkien","Roald Dahl","Lewis Carroll"],"question":"Who penned the words, 'Hubble, bubble toil and trouble, fire burn and cauldron bubble'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Bay City Rollers","incorrectAnswers":["Status Quo","The Who","Cream"],"question":"Who Had 2 Number One LP's Called \"Rollin\" & \"Once Upon A Star\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Divan","incorrectAnswers":["The Ottoman","The Futon","The Chaise Lounge"],"question":"What was the name of the Ottoman Empire's governing body?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bahrain","incorrectAnswers":["Eritrea","Israel","Djibouti"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Saudi Arabia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Feudalism","incorrectAnswers":["Polygamy","Communism","Oligarchy"],"question":"What medieval social system was based on the holding of land in exchange for labor?","difficulty":"hard"},